Survey of the John Chamberlain papers
Hoover Institution Archives
John Chamberlain papers
1943-1990
86004
Hoover Institution Archives
164 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (66.8 linear feet)
Writings, correspondence, and printed matter, relating to world affairs, American politics, economic conditions in the United States, conservative political philosophy, and laissez-faire economics. Most of the material consists of drafts and printed copies of newspaper columns and other writings by Chamberlain.
Chamberlain, John, 1903-
Access
Boxes 163-165 closed pending preservation treatment.
The remainder of the collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least two business days in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1986.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at https://searchworks.stanford.edu. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
American journalist.
Scope and Content of Collection
Writings, correspondence, and printed matter, relating to world affairs, American politics, economic conditions in the United States, conservative political philosophy, and laissez-faire economics. Most of the material consists of drafts and printed copies of newspaper columns and other writings by Chamberlain.
Conservatism.; Journalists.; Laissez-faire.; United States--Economic conditions--1945-; United States--Politics and government--1945-1989.; World politics--1945-1989.
- Correspondence
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes letters, notes, clippings sent to and from Chamberlain.
  - Correspondence, 1965-1970 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1983 (Box 48)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1985 (Box 49)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 79)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1972 (Box 118)
  - Correspondence, 1956-1962 (Box 119)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1970 (Box 124)
- Speeches and Writings
  Includes newspaper clippings, receipts of articles, notes, reviews, drafts, publications and research associated with Chamberlain and by other authors.
  - Speeches and Writings, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1968-1970 (Box 3)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1980-1982 (Box 4)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1961-1968 (Box 6)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1967-1969 (Box 7)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1963-1969 (Box 8)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1969-1970 (Box 11)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1966-1969 (Box 12)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1963-1967 (Box 13)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1963-1964 (Box 14)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1981-1982 (Box 15)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1971-1982 (Box 16)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1963-1971 (Box 17)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1974 (Box 18)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1974 (Box 19)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1967-1973 (Box 20)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1969-1970 (Box 21)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1973-1974 (Box 22)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1969 (Box 23)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1969 (Box 24)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1969 (Box 25)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1969-1970 (Box 26)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1970 (Box 27)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1970-1971 (Box 28)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1971 (Box 29)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1971 (Box 30)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1971-1977 (Box 31)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1975-1977 (Box 32)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1977 (Box 33)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1977-1979 (Box 34)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1979 (Box 35)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1979 (Box 36)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1977-1979 (Box 37)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1977-1979 (Box 38)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1977-1979 (Box 39)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1979 (Box 40)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1978-1979 (Box 41)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1979 (Box 42)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1979 (Box 43)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1981-1982 (Box 44)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1979-1982 (Box 45)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1981 (Box 46)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1981 (Box 47)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1972-1983 (Box 48)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1985 (Box 50)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1985 (Box 51)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1985 (Box 52)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1985 (Box 53)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1984-1985 (Box 54)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1984 (Box 55)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1983-1984 (Box 56)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1983 (Box 57)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1983 (Box 58)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1983 (Box 59)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1982-1983 (Box 60)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1973-1982 (Box 61)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1972-1973 (Box 62)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1971-1973 (Box 63)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1982 (Box 64)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1982-1984 (Box 65)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1984 (Box 66)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1984 (Box 67)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1984 (Box 68)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1984 (Box 69)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1983 (Box 70)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1983 (Box 71)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1983 (Box 72)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1983 (Box 73)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1976 (Box 74)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1976 (Box 75)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1976 (Box 76)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1976 (Box 77)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1976 (Box 78)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1968-1969 (Box 79)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1971-1973 (Box 80)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1971, 1980-1985 (Box 81)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1978 (Box 82)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1971-1978 (Box 83)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1978 (Box 84)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1978 (Box 85)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1978 (Box 86)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1978 (Box 87)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1950-1969 (Box 88)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1978 (Box 89)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1956-1966 (Box 90)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1956-1963 (Box 91)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1956-1963 (Box 92)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1956-1963 (Box 93)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1963-1986 (Box 94)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1964-1984 (Box 95)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1982 (Box 96)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1982 (Box 97)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1971-1974 (Box 98)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1974-1975 (Box 99)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1963, 1970-1974 (Box 100)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1975 (Box 101)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1981 (Box 102)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1972-1974 (Box 103)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1981 (Box 104)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1981 (Box 105)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1972-1981 (Box 106)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1972 (Box 107)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1972 (Box 108)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1972-1978 (Box 109)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1979-1980 (Box 110)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1980 (Box 111)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1980 (Box 112)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1980 (Box 113)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1977-1980 (Box 114)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1977 (Box 115)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1977 (Box 116)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1977 (Box 117)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1956-1962 (Box 119)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1957-1980 (Box 120)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1975-1980 (Box 121)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1975 (Box 122)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1968-1973 (Box 123)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1967-1972 (Box 125)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1964-1972 (Box 126)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1975 (Box 127)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1959-1986 (Box 128)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1963-1986 (Box 129)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1963 (Box 130)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1965 (Box 131)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1965-1966 (Box 132)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1966-1967 (Box 133)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1967-1968 (Box 134)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1968-1987 (Box 135)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1986 (Box 136)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1987 (Box 137)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1986-1987 (Box 138)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1986-1987 (Box 139)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1987 (Box 140)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1987 (Box 141)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1987-1988 (Box 142)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1988 (Box 143)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1988 (Box 144)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1988 (Box 145)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1988 (Box 146)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1985-1989 (Box 147)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1985 (Box 148)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1985-1989 (Box 149)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1985-1986 (Box 150)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1985-1986 (Box 151)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1986 (Box 152)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1986 (Box 153)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1986-1987 (Box 154)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1987-1989 (Box 155)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1986-1989 (Box 156)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1987-1989 (Box 157)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1989 (Box 158)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1989-1990 (Box 159)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1989 (Box 160)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1989 (Box 161)
- Speaking Engagements and Appearances
  Includes invitations, records of events, awards and other documents related to events attended by Chamberlain.
  - Speaking Engagements and Appearances, 1972-1982 (Box 48)
  - Speaking Engagements and Appearances, 1972-1985 (Box 49)
  - Speaking Engagements and Appearances, 1950-1969 (Box 88)
  - Speaking Engagements and Appearances, 1956-1966 (Box 90)
  - Speaking Engagements and Appearances, 1962-1970 (Box 124)
  - Speaking Engagements and Appearances, 1986-1987 (Box 154)
- Miscellaneous, 1961-1990
  Scope and Content note
  Includes an assortment of notes, research, correspondence, undated publications, etc. from Chamberlain and other writers.
  - Miscellaneous, 1967-1982 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1967-1973 (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous, 1968-1969 (Box 79)
  - Miscellaneous, 1950-1969 (Box 88)
  - Miscellaneous, 1963-1986 (Box 94)
  - Miscellaneous, 1975-1980 (Box 121)
  - Miscellaneous, 1968-1973 (Box 123)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960-1975 (Box 118)
  - Miscellaneous, 1962-1970 (Box 124)
  - Miscellaneous, 1986-1987 (Box 139)
  - Miscellaneous, 1987-1989 (Box 155)
  - Miscellaneous, 1987-1987 (Box 157)
  - Miscellaneous, 1989 (Box 158)
  - Miscellaneous, 1989-1990 (Box 159)
  - Closed pending preservation treatment (Boxes 163-165)
- Oversized materials, 1979-1981 (Box 162)
  Includes oversized magazines and newspaper prints.